Ladies and gentlemen, behold all 66 of
new Minnesota Viking Caleb Banks from
the University of Florida. He was the
18th overall pick in the first round by
the Minnesota Vikings and he's nice
enough to join us here uh specifically
at the Vikings Entertainment Network,
part of the Minnesota Vikings
organization for a guy who said you were
excited to become a Viking.
>> Absolutely.
>> Why was that?
>> Um honestly just all around the people
in the building, you know what I mean?
And um everybody here is uh great
people. I'm a people person. So um once
I get that connection, you know what I
mean? I just want to be around them all
the time. So u felt that off off the rip
and I'm like let's do it.
>> And and you know once they got to 18,
you know, and and you pro did you have a
good idea you'd go in the first round or
was it kind of weird because of what
everybody was writing and saying and
stuff?
>> Yeah. Um I mean I don't really listen to
it. Uh you know, you see it but um I
really try not to like you know listen
to that cuz they don't some people
really don't know anything. You know
what I mean? But my agent called me. He
was like it's a chance it could happen.
It's a chance it might not happen. So, I
was prepared um for it to happen and for
it not to happen, you know what I mean?
Mentally mentally there.
>> Now, now when the the picks are falling
up to 18. Yeah.
>> And you probably had a pretty good idea
that the Minnesota Vikings were really
interested in you specifically
>> after defensive line coach Ryan Nielsen
came down to Florida to sit down with
you and talk to you. Yes, sir.
>> But there are no promises as you kind of
just said. So, as the picks were
falling, how were you handling it? Like,
is it a nerve-wracking experience? Um,
it is, but I was more so excited for the
guys that was getting picked, you know
what I mean? Uh, some of the guys I was
at the senior bowl with, some of them I
trained with. Um, like I think like four
of our guy, four A1 athletes, a U
athlete first athletes went um, I think
top 10 and that was pretty dope. You
know what I mean? Seeing them boys live
their dreams.
>> Um, I was really excited for him. So, it
was kind of like just watching that like
watching them, you know, be successful.
I'm like, okay. Like, you know what I
mean? Congratulations. It really wasn't
a, oh man, like am I going to get
picked? You know what I mean? So, um, it
was a great it was a great moment.
>> Well, that's awesome. And um uh number
95 is that what you're going to wear
here?
>> Absolutely.
>> Okay. Why 95?
>> I don't know. They they asked me. You
got four four numbers to pick from.
>> I just said just give me 95.
>> Well, I mean, you know how the process
works? Like if there's a number you feel
like you have to have,
>> unless it's unless it's retired or
unless it's in the ring of honor or
whatever, you know, there are ways to
get that number. So, 95 is going to be
the number and you feel good about it.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Excellent. Um, how um how tired are you
quite honestly of doctors and trainers
poking and proddding at your feet and
messing with your feet?
>> Yeah, I mean um I don't want to say I'm
used to it, but uh I mean it's happened
a couple times. Um you know, they they
got to they got to do their job. So um
you know what I mean? I let them do
their job. You go ahead look at it.
Everything's good. We're good to go.
>> Uh this uh this facility, Twin Cities
Orthopedics Performance Center, it's uh
considered one of the one of the very
best, if not the very best in the NFL.
>> I haven't seen anything better. What do
you think? I mean, you you this is going
to be home for you pretty much from, I
don't know, rookie camp through mini
camp, then you get a little break, then
you get training camp in the season. I
don't know how much you've seen of it
yet, but what do you think? What do you
like?
>> Um, I mean, honestly, it's beautiful,
man. The purple and gold. Seeing it
everywhere. I can't I turn my head, I
see it there. I turn my head, I see it
there, man. And that's it's honestly
just it is beautiful. You know what I
mean? Um, I'm excited to be here. Uh,
and I can't wait to get to work, man.
>> So, playing for the Gator and um, you
know, playing a certain team that uh,
wears purple and gold. Yeah. Well,
>> it's got to be a little strange for you,
right? To be to be bragging about purple
and gold, you know, when you might have
LSU on your mind for a little bit.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. I mean, um ah
you got me there.
>> Well, we got Justin Jefferson, too, so
you got to remember that. So, you got to
show respect, you know, to that to that
form of purple.
>> Yeah. I'm just I'm going just turn on a
few clips from 24, man, when we was
going against him and 25.
>> Oh, that's great. um a as a as a 66
defensive lineman when everything's
healthy and happy, what advantages does
your size generally give you against
offensive linemen, say centers and
guards, but generally speaking, what
advantages do you have because of the
the gifts God has given you?
>> Yeah, absolutely. I mean, I think it's
really just um my athleticism. I think a
lot not a lot of guys have that. Um I
feel like I'm kind of like a jack of all
trades and one in one, you know what I
mean? Um I'm different and I can move in
different ways. I can I got a lot of a
lot of tools where I can beat you and
you never know what's coming. So, um
>> it's kind of random.
>> Well, I mean, you say you're a jack of
all trades, specifically one-on-one, and
that's absolutely true. And if you
weren't, you wouldn't have been drafted
in the first round. But in watching back
some of your plays from 2024, I mean,
honestly, there aren't a lot of one-on-
ones. Yeah. You know, so going to the
NFL against people who have been in the
league for a while, grown men, so to
speak. Do you expect that or or you kind
of have to earn the right to be as
frustrating as being doubled can be when
you earn the right that that kind of uh
indicates that you belong, right?
>> Absolutely. Yeah. Uh and I think that's
just going to take a lot of hard work.
Uh you know, put my head down and coming
in and being a sponge and learning from
the vets. Um learning how to, you know,
take on those blocks or learning what
what I should expect in the game. So um
that's my goal. It's my ultimate goal
coming in and just working so I can get
to that point.
>> From uh from when you went to high
school outside of Detroit, from then to
where you are now in including the first
round draft process. Uh how has your
family been instrumental to you during
the whole way?
>> Yeah. Um man, they just been really
supportive. Uh they they're happy and
they it's like they got drafted too, you
know what I mean? Uh they're really
excited for me and um it's like a dream
come true for me, you know what I Uh,
nobody I honestly didn't think I would
be in this situation to be in these, you
know, in these in these shoes. And, uh,
you know, God put me here. So, I'm
blessed to be here and, um, I'm going to
take every single
I'm going to take all advantage of it.
You know what I mean? I'm taking a run
with it. So,
>> So, so your brothers are quite good at
basketball, correct?
>> Yeah. Yeah. They hoop. Yep.
>> Yeah. What uh So, why didn't you follow
in their footsteps, especially at 66?
>> Yeah. Uh, man, I was I was aggressive.
Too aggressive.
>> Oh, yeah. Shocker. I like your
highlights. I mean, there was a personal
protector on an LSU punt play. You may
remember this.
>> Jack Pipurn. That's my
>> I don't know the guy's name. Holy cow.
You knocked him into next week.
>> Yeah, it was a little personal, too. He
actually seen me at the senior bowl. He
was No, he seen me at the combine. He
was like, "Man, why'd you do that, bro?"
I'm like,
>> "Bro, I had to, bro. You wanted to leave
us like that. You want to go there out
of all places?" Okay. So, I have
>> So, you're naturally aggressive, which
works in basketball.
>> Yeah. And um and I'm competitive, so um
I'm I'm going to get after it. Um and I
wanted to do something different, you
know what I mean? And I stuck behind my
mom back to play football. And u ever
since then, it's been history. It's been
a dream come true for me. So, so when
did you know whether it's full speed on
that punk coverage team when you were a
Gator uh or playing defensive line with
running backs, quarterbacks, uh
horizontally, vertically, or whatever.
When did you know that you like to run
fast and hit people?
>> Um, I mean, it all started really in
high school when I first started
playing.
>> Um,
>> just like it it was just fun to me, you
know what I mean? It's like being able
to physically oppose my will on somebody
else and not not get in trouble for it.
So, I think that's really the best part
of it.
>> Uh, now the defensive coordinator here
for the Minnesota Vikings, Brian Flores,
super well respected. What um what do
you know as of now about Brian and it's
very early in the process, but his
expectations for defensive lineman with
all these tricks he has up his sleeve.
>> Yeah. Um, you know, he just told me to
come in and put my head down. uh we
gonna get to that point when we get
there, but uh he really want me to work
right now, you know, work my tail off,
you know, so I can get back healthy,
fully healthy, and be out there to go to
uh dominate um you know uh and be there
for the guys. So, uh yeah, but I I he
told me I could play anywhere on that on
that defensive line, man. So, it's kind
of,
>> you know, it's it's going to be fun.
>> At your press conference, you you
mentioned your adoration, your your
desire to own and your love for animals.
>> Absolutely.
>> So, then I'm, you know, thinking like,
all right, what's he going to say about
Photo? What's he going to say about
Spot? How many kitties does he have?
>> Well, then then you hit us with a couple
of pythons.
>> Yeah.
>> Um this super aggressive looking dog.
What's it called?
>> King Corso.
>> Holy cow. That's a chest. And uh that
you know you you hope to advance your
animal loving life through owning a
tarantula. Yeah.
>> Like a tarantula, right?
>> Yeah. Yeah. Little spider. Yeah, man. Um
>> how do you play with a tarantula?
>> Uh no, you can't. That's the thing. You
can't really play with
>> Be stimulated, too.
>> Yeah. No. Um I don't I just got a I got
a big love for animals, man. Um, ever
since I was younger, I fell in love with
them. I just wanted to, you know, know
everything about them. Wanted to be a
zoologologist, but I really didn't have
the time because of football, so it was
a little bit different for me. But, um,
now once I got my first snake, I was
like, "Okay." They said, "You're going
to get another one." I'm like, "No, I
might just get one."
>> Went and got another one. And then I
went and got another one.
>> Yeah.
>> So, it was it was it's crazy, man. I got
a chameleon. I plan on getting a few
more lizards. Uh,
>> lies.
>> Uh, lizards. Lizards.
>> Oh, lizards. Okay. Like, whoa. Okay.
>> Yeah. No, I love chameleons, though. um
the way how they express theelves too.
So it's beautiful.
>> So So I mean like what do you do with
pythons? Do you roll around with them?
Can you play? Like do they get to know
you so they know, hey, Caleb's the
owner. He has the food. We have to be
nice to Caleb. I mean, are snakes like
that?
>> Um they are they have different
personalities. So some snakes are a
little bit more aggressive than others.
I have two ball pythons, so they're a
little bit um less aggressive. They're
not really They're like more of a a
starter snake pet, um I would say. Um
but they're wonderful, though. They're
they're wonderful. They're two females.
Uh and they're beautiful. They have um
beautiful coats. Um they they're very
nice. You know, when they they they see
their food, they're going to attack the
food. They ain't really attack they
ain't attack me yet.
>> What is their food? Uh they eat like
rats.
>> Okay. Yeah. Yeah.
>> Well, I mean, last one here, I promise.
This is just fascinating. Holy cow.
>> So, with the pythons and given you
played in Gainesville,
>> which is in Florida.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. You ever think of taking those
pythons down to like some water area and
look around, see if any alligators are
there and just like let them go at each
other and see what happens? I don't
think my pythons will make it through
with some alligators.
>> But
>> maybe it's their version of the combine.
>> Yeah. Yeah. No, but I I don't think I'd
come back home with them. I probably
come home with alligator at that point.
So,
>> you're fantastic.
>> Thank you.
>> God bless you and your family, man. I
can't wait to call your games and man,
it's it's a dream come true for you and
your family and welld deserved.
>> Thank you so much. God bless you. Caleb
Banks, a new member of the Minnesota
Vikings.